《死神来了》
(法国观光)
(推销员之死)
(一命呜呼)
艾力克斯
Alex.
托德和乔治的爸爸刚刚来电话
Tod and George's dad just called.
他说明天下午3:30来接你
He's picking you up at 3.30 tomorrow.
五点巴士从学校出发
The bus leaves the high school for the airport around 5.00.
我的皮包好用吗?
How's my suitcase working out for you?
妈妈 不要拆标签
Mom,you got to leave that on.
爸爸上次带着标签搭飞机…
The tag made the last flight without the plane crashing...
没有出事 应该保留
so I figure it's got to be on or with the bag.
是吉祥物
For luck.
胡思乱想
Where would you get a nutball idea like that?
我的确还活着
I'm still here.
你才17岁
So,seventeen,on the loose...
你们这群野马
senior trip with your friends in Paris...
到巴黎渡假十日
ten days in the springtime.
趁青春 好好开心吧
Live it up.You got your whole life ahead of you.
比利 让叔叔帮你一下
Hitchcock,let me give you a hand with this.
给你
There you go.
混球
Carter,you dick.
小子
Schmuck.
- 你遗留在巴士上的 - 谢谢
- You left this on the bus. - Thanks.
来吧 让我们帮你拿点行李吧
Come on let's get your stuff together.
嘘 姬丝黛…贝丽…
Hey,Christa.Hi,Blake.
- 做什么? - 你们的爸爸
- What are you doing? - He's the man.
带齐行李没有?
All right.You guys got everything?
爸 都带齐了
Yeah,Dad,we're all set.
意思是指可以起程吗?
Does that mean go?
不知道
Don't know.
这是给你们两个的 玩得开心
This is for both of you.Have a great time.
谢谢 爸爸
Thanks,Dad.
- 是给我们两个的 - 走吧
- Both of us. - Let's go.
- 艾力克斯 照顾一下他们 - 我会的
- Alex,take care of them. - I will.
校刊上我的照片真恶心
Didn't think anything could look worse than my yearbook photo.
别烦我 从早到晚就听你罗嗦
How do you think I feel having to look at you?
他叽里咕噜什么?
What the fuck does he want?
机上不准乘客生事
The airport does not endorse solicitors.
死 并非一了百了
Death is not the end.
(世界并非只有物质)
再骚扰我学生 你就一了百了
It will be for you if you harass my students.
神会保佑你
Hare Rama.
我想问你几句
I have to ask you a few questions this evening.
行李是你自己收拾?
Did you pack your bags yourself?
一直在你身边?
Have your belongings been in your possession the entire time?
(取消)
- 布郎宁先生? - 是我
- Mr Browning? - Oh Yeah
你有没有接过陌生人的东西?
Have you received any packages from persons unknown to you?
(终点:巴黎戴高乐机场)
- 和你生日一样 - 什么?
- Same as your birthday. - What?
你生于9月25日,起飞是9点25分
September 25.9.25.
生日和起飞时间一样
Your birthday's the same as your departure time.
(终点)
滚开!迪克
Fuck off,dude.Dick.
小子
Babe.
老爸说给的钱我们两个都有份
George,Dad said both of us.Give me some cash.
嗨…不要闹了
Hi! Hi! Knock it off.
混蛋
You asshole.
(巴黎观光)
- 谢谢 - 不用客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
一起去拉屎
Let's go take a shit.
- 你自己去拉个够 - 不 一起去
- Take a shit by yourself. - No,dude.
嘿 听着 不如讲些有意思的吧
Listen OK? Take some knowledge.
七个钟头飞机
We're about to board a seven-hour flight.
机上厕所不通风
The toilets in coach are barely ventilated closets.
飞到半路
Say halfway through the flight...
你进去拉屎
your body wants that aeroplane food out.
拉完屎出来
You got to go torque a wicked cable.
万一姬丝黛或者贝丽接着进去…
Then directly after you,walks in Christa or Blake.
见到你留在马桶内的杰作…
Want them to associate you with that watery sting in their eye?
不反胃才怪
That reflexive gag at the back of their throat?
是约翰?丹华唱的
John Denver.
撞机死…
Died in a plane crash.
各位先生女士请注意
Ladies and gentlemen,thank you for your patience.
飞往巴黎的180号班机…
At this time,we would like to begin preboarding...
…即将登机 乘客们请前往46号登机口
of Volee Air flight 180 to Paris through gate 46.
有人看见比利?希治格吗?
Anyone seen Billy Hitchcock? How did we lose him?
走 走
Go.Go.
走
Go.
好痛
That hurt.
飞机上有小孩 多数不会失事
That's a good sign.Younger,the better.
否则上帝必定心理变态
It'd be a fucked-up God to take down this plane.
也许真的变态
A really fucked-up God.
- 嘿 托德 - 你好
- Hey,Tod. - Hello.How you doing?
你可以跟姬丝黛换个位置吗?
Can you switch seats with Christa?
可以 但我随时要小便
God,I would,but I got a bladder thing.
尿道发炎
It's a urinary tract infection.
问问艾力克斯吧
Let's go ask Alex.
艾力克斯 换个位?我想和贝丽坐一起
Could you trade seats so Blake and I could sit together?
她问过托德 他说他得了什么病
She asked Tod,but he had some medical thing.
- 求求你 - 好吧
- Please? - Yeah
你真是个好人 艾力克斯
You're so sweet.Thanks,Alex.
谢谢你 艾力克斯
Thank you,Alex.
不用客气…
You're welcome.
你以为在飞机上可以泡到马子吗?
You really think we'd titty-fuck them over Greenland?
搞得我吃得都没胃口 全程只看一级片
Because of you,I got to watch fucking "Stuart Little"
谢谢你
Thank you.
你还真够朋友
Thanks man.That's great.
抱歉迟到
Sorry I'm late.
那是我的座位
That's my seat right there.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 喂? - 出发
- Hello? - Ain't going that way.
请大家注意
May I have your attention?
请各位系好
To properly fasten your seat belts...
安全带
slide the flat portion into the buckle.
机上其有6个紧急出口
There are six emergency exits.
两个在前 两个位于机翼侧
Two doors in front two over the wings...
还有那个在后边
two at the rear of the aircraft.
服务员 准备起飞
Flight attendants,prepare for departure.
好的
All right.
不要紧
Whatever.
不要怕
It's fine.
没事的 亲爱的
It's OK honey.
艾力克斯 换个位?我想和贝丽坐一起
Alex? Could you trade seats so Blake and I could sit together?
她问过托德 他说他得了什么病
She asked Tod,but he had some medical thing.
求求你
Please?
什么事?
What's up,dude?
- 先生 什么事? - 搞什么鬼?
- Is there a problem,sir? - What's your fucking problem?
飞机会爆炸!
This fucking plane's going to explode!
- 闭嘴!布郎宁 - 搞什么鬼?
- Shut up,Browning. - You're so not funny.
- 不应该开玩笑… - 不是开玩笑!
- If this is a joke... - It's not a joke!
艾力克斯 真的
Alex,take it easy.
- 飞机会坠毁 - 乱讲
- Sit down! - It's going down!
你们可能要下飞机
We'll remove you if this continues.
我自己会下的
I'll fucking remove myself!
- 那个座位是我的 - 游戏会继续进行
- That's my seat. - This plane is going down!
通道上的人 全都下去
Everybody in the aisle off the plane.
大家都坐好!
Just stay where you are.Sit tight.
坐好 飞机会坠毁
This fucking plane is going down!
- 你跟他去 照顾他一下 - 好的
- Go check him out.See how he's doing. - Ok
- 我没有闹事 放手! - 放手 混蛋
- Get the fuck off me! - Let go,jerk.
看着他 不要放他们上机
You got this? No one gets back on board.
- 这是我的命令 - 等一等
- That's my call. - Wait,please!
我有40个学生去巴黎
I've got forty students going to Paris.Please.
请明白我的立场
You must understand my position.
十分抱歉
I do,and I apologize for Alex...
机上的学生不能没有教师
but one of us needs to be on that plane.
我不能让这些学生自己去巴黎10天的时间
I cannot let those students go to Paris for ten days...
卡特 停手!坐下 卡特!
Sit the fuck down,Carter! Sit!
你们之中 只准一个上机
One of you can go on the flight.
拉里
Larry.
机师态度强硬 只准你或我上机
They're not taking this well.One of us can get back on.
我们迟三个小时后搭另一班
The rest can take an 11.10 flight.
我留下来
I'll stay.
你上机吧 你懂法语
You know the French thing.Get on the plane.
很好
It's fine.
我刚才上了厕所 才出来…
Hi,I was in the bathroom,and the lock was stuck...
等一等 我没有生事!
Wait,I didn't fight with anyone!
岂有此理
Damn!
谢谢
Thanks.
你父母正在赶来
I called your parents.They're on their way.
蠢货
Stupid Alex.
艾力克斯 究竟什么事?
Alex,talk to me.Tell me what happened.
我看见…
I saw it.
I don't know.I saw it.
看见飞机从跑道起飞
l saw it on the runway,I saw it take off...
我从窗口望出去 望到地面
I saw out my window,I saw the ground.
机舱开始震动
And the cabin,it starts to shake.
左边飞脱 跟着飞机爆炸
The left side blows up and the whole plane explodes.
看得清清楚楚 和真的一样
And it was so real,like how everything happens.
你见惯飞机爆炸?
Been on a lot of planes that blew up?
你必定睡着了
You fell asleep.
我们延迟半日去巴黎…
We get thrown off the plane and blow a half day in Paris?
只因为艾力克斯做他妈的噩梦?
All because Browning has a bad fucking dream?
不过 且慢…糟了 飞机会爆炸 飞机会爆炸…
Wait! The plane,it's going to blow up!
去死吧!卡特
Fuck you,Horton.
去巴黎?进医院就有你份!
The only trip you're taking is to the fucking hospital!
放开他! 艾力克斯 住手!
Get off him ! Alex,stop it!
眼巴巴看着别人去
There they go,here we stay.
我要你赔偿
You're paying for my trip.
可惜你没留在机上
I wish you were on that plane!
- 贱人! - 哦 见鬼!
- You fucking prick! - Shit!
- 快打电话 - 安保!
- Call it in! - Security!
为什么望着我?
You're looking at me as if I caused this.
不关我的事
I didn't cause this.
有没有人生还?
Are there any survivors?
我怎么会知道?
How should I know?
- 我没有… - 这不是巫术
- You think I'm some... - He's not a witch.
我叫薛高
I'm Howard Seigel...
运输安全局
National Transportation and Safety Board.
你们的家人接到通知
We've contacted all your families.
正赶来的途中
They are on the way.
谁要见医生?
Is there anyone here who feels they might need...
谁要见神父或是牧师?
medical attention or spiritual counselling?
什么事?有没有人生还?
What's going on? Are there any survivors?
爆炸的原因未明
The cause for the explosion is still undetermined.
救援队抵达现场后…
The Nassau County authorities are on the scene...
展开海上搜索
naval search and rescue en route.
打扰一下 我是温纳
Excuse me.I'm Agent Weine.
这位是希瑞克 联邦调查局探员
This is Agent Schreck.We're with the FBl.
我明白你们的心情
I understand how you all must be feeling...
这对你们非常的困难…
and I know it's going to be difficult...
趁记忆犹新…
but we need to ask questions regarding today's events...
我们不得不问几句话
while they're still fresh in your mind.
无论对于拯救 调查…
This will prove invaluable to our rescue attempts...
你们所提供的数据 都很有用
and any potential criminal investigation.
你说:听我说…
You said,"Listen to me.
飞机起飞后会爆炸
"This plane will explode on takeoff."
你怎知道?
How did you know that?
我有预感
I got this feeling.
奇怪的预感
This weird feeling.
你有没有服过镇定剂?
Did you take any sedatives before boarding?
在飞机上你有没有服用过
On board,did you take any sleeping pills...
安眠药 或迷幻药?
narcotics,hallucinogens?
吸不吸毒?
Do you take any drugs?
我预先见到
I saw it.
见到将会发生的事
I saw it happen.
见到飞机爆炸
I saw the plane explode.
爆炸前 你说…
Did the weird feelings have anything to do...
"可惜卡特没留在机上"
with your saying you wished Carter Horton was on it...
你那样说 因为预感?
just before it exploded?
那么 为什么那样说?
Then why'd you say it?
我不以为飞机真的会爆炸
I didn't really think it was going to happen.
既然如此…
If that's the case,Alex...
为什么下飞机?
why did you really get off the plane?
哥哥叫我下飞机…
My brother George...
照顾艾力克斯
he told me to go keep an eye on Alex.
于是哥哥留在机上
And so he stayed and...
而我下机
He told me to get off the plane.
拉利叫我上机
Larry Murnau said I should get back on...
但我认为他上机比较适合
but I told him that he should go.
我叫他上机
I sent him back on the plane.
是的
All right.
没有人逼你下飞机
Nobody forced you off the plane.
你跟下飞机的同学也不熟
You said you weren't friends with those that were...
克莱尔 那么你为什么下飞机?
so,Clear,why did you get off the plane?
因为我看到 听到艾力克斯的情形
Because I saw and I heard Alex...
因为我相信他
and I believed him.
他在那里
There he is.
谢谢你送我回来
Thank you for the ride.
9点25分 180号班机…
You are looking at the first piece of debris...
从纽约肯尼迪机场起飞
to wash ashore from Volee Air flight 180...
随即发生爆炸 爆炸碎片…
which erupted shortly after a 9.25 p.m.takeoff...
开始冲上沙滩
from John F.Kennedy Airport in New York.
据悉未有生还者
There are no known survivors.
飞机燃料仍在海面燃烧
Coast Guard and naval search and rescue efforts...
水警与海军…
are continuing at this moment...
正在海上搜索
even as jet fuel burns on the ocean's surface.
对于寻获生还者的机会…
Authorities are pessimistic about the possibility...
当局认为微乎其微
of finding anyone alive from the ill-fated flight.
287名乘客 可能全部遇难
All 287 passengers are feared dead.
其中有
Amongst the travellers...
来自阿伯拉罕山中学…
a class of forty students and four teachers...
40名学生 4位教师
from Mount Abraham High School in south-east New York...
该批师生拟赴巴黎参观
en route to Paris on a field trip.
起机前
There are reports several students...
数名学生因事…
were removed from the aircraft moments before departure...
被驱逐下机 不过…
however,investigators remain guarded...
详情未获披露
about the specifics of this incident.
运输安全局和联邦调查局…
Authorities from National Transportation and Safety...
两局人员已经到抵达现场…
and the Federal Bureau of lnvestigation...
着手调查
have arrived at JFKto begin the initial investigation.
机场与附近的长岛…
Eyewitnesses at the airport,as well as on Long lsland...
都有人目击这次爆炸意外
report seeing the plane explode.
肇事上空 当时并没有其它飞机
No other aircraft were visibly near flight 180.
航机控制员…
At JFK,air traffic controllers...
正研究目击者口供
are corroborating these eyewitness accounts.
爆炸碎片…
After the explosion,debris apparently rained...
散播在大西洋数英里范围
into the Atlantic Ocean for several miles.
目前 调查人员…
Investigators are cautious about verifying these accounts...
仍未能确定…
believing they'll learn more...
39日前…
Thirty-nine days have passed...
我们痛失39位
since we lost our thirty-nine loved ones...
亲爱师友
friends,and teachers.
空难的原因
As each day passes...
一日未查明…
without a determining cause for the accident...
我们的心结一日不能解开
we ask ourselves,"Why?"
圣经《传道书》这样说…
"Ecclesiastes" tells us...
死亡何时出现 殊难逆料
"Man no more knows his own time...
人就像网中鱼…
"than fish taken in the fatal net...
笼中鸟…
"or birds trapped in the snare.
死 往往突如其来
"Like these,the children of men caught...
听天由命而已
"when the time falls suddenly upon them."
正当伤痛犹新
And so,before we can heal...
死亡阴霾 徘徊未散
before we escape the presence of death and time...
我们谨立此碑…
we must mourn and celebrate theirs...
悼念亡魂
with this memorial.
你不要自以为…
I hope you don't think because my name ain't on this wall...
是我的救命恩人
that I owe you anything.
我没有
l don't.
他们死去 我更应该好好地活
All I owe these people is to live my life to the fullest.
那就少饮酒为妙
Why don't you stay off the J.D.,then?
你没资格干涉
Don't you ever fucking tell me what to do.
我的命掌握在我自己手上
I control my life,not you.
我不会死的
I'm never going to die.
我在考车牌
I took my driver's test last week at the DMV.
考到最低分
Got a seventy.
不过 总算及格
It's the lowest score you can get,but I passed.
你知道不 当我在路考时…
The thing is,when I was done with the test...
考牌官对我说了什么?
you know the guy that drives with you during the test?
他说…
Anyways,he goes....
"年青人 你会英年早丧"
"Young man,you're going to die at a very young age."
我真的短命?
Is that true?
放心好了 你吉人天相
Not now,not here,not ever,Billy.
那我可以约仙迪出去了?
If I ask out Cynthia Paster,will she say no?
见鬼…
Fuck.
不要跟我交谈 我怕了你
Don't talk to me.You scare the hell out of me.
我来了
I'm going up.
不要误会 不过…
I don't want you to take this the wrong way.
我会记住你的
I miss you,you know?
我也会记的你的
Yeah,I miss you,too.
可是我爸爸不明白
But my father,he doesn't understand.
等他心情平复…
Look,when he gets over this thing...
你和我一同出城散散心
you and me,we'll road trip to the city...
去看扬基棒球队
catch the Yanks.
一言为定
We'll do that.
好极
Cool.
我还是走了
I better go.
悼念文章
This thing Ms Lewton showed me in class...
柳敦老师叫我朗诵
they're going to let me read it.
正说出我的心声
It says what I'm feeling.
保重
Take care,man.
全靠你 我还活着
Because of you,I'm still alive.
谢谢
Thank you.
俗语说 死期难料
We say that the hour of death cannot be forecast.
话虽如此 其实…
But when we say this...
我们心底把自己的死亡…
we imagine that the hour is placed...
当作遥不可及的一回事
in an obscure and distant future.
做梦也想不到…
It never occurs to us that it has any connection...
自己的生命…
with the day already begun...
可能随时终结
or that death could arrive this same afternoon.
可能今天 今午
This afternoon which is so certain...
甚至可能 此时此刻
and which has every hour filled in advance.
(火灾与爆炸)
(各种空难)
(空难)
(机场运作)
(学生悼念会昨天举行)
(阁楼杂志)
(托德)
(黑箱车)
什么事?
What happened?
托德呢?
Where's Tod?
快离开这里!
Get out of here.
- 你预见不到吗? - 什么事?
- Didn't you see it? - What happened?
托德下机 而哥哥没下机 你令他觉得很内疚
You caused Tod so much guilt over George...
于是自杀
he took his own life.
听着 他不可能自杀
Look! He wouldn't do that.
如果他想自杀 怎么会说…
Okey? He said we'd be friends again after you got better.
等你心情平复 约我出去玩?
Why would he make plans if he was going to kill himself?
华格纳先生!
Mr Waggner.
几乎成秋天了
Almost autumn.
只是六月底
It's only the end of June.
但什么都在转变
Yeah,but everything's always in transition.
只要留意 即使在现在
If you focus,even now,just one week into summer...
你也会感到秋意转浓
you can almost feel autumn coming.
我喜欢预测未来
I like being able to see the future.
你昨晚为什么去托德家?
Why were you at Tod's house last night?
我从电视里知道…
I've seen enough TV to know...
联邦探员去托德家
the FBl doesn't investigate teen suicides.
不是调查自杀
They were there last night.That means,one...
而是调查撞机
they still don't have a clue what caused the crash.
他们至今还没有头绪
they haven't ruled out anything...
七个人事先离开飞机
and the fact seven people got off the plane...
已经够奇怪了
is probably weird enough.
其中一个有异能
Not to mention,one of those people had a vision...
预见飞机爆炸
Whatever....of the plane exploding...
飞机果然爆炸 那就是奇上加奇
minutes before it actually did is highly suspicious.
最可疑的是
And it doesn't help that the visionary's friend...
他的朋友自杀
just committed suicide.
你昨晚为什么去?
Why were you there last night?
这塑像是谁 知不知道?
You know what this is?
是…
This is a...
弹簧头是谁?
This is Springy Head Guy.
是你 不求形似 只求神似
It's you.Not a likeness.
你带给我的感觉
It's how you make me feel,Alex.
对不起
I'm sorry.
像你一样
No.Like you,the sculpture doesn't even know...
塑像不知情由
what or why it is.
无所适从
It's reluctant to take form...
却肯定有一个理念
and yet creating an absolute...
一个抽像而不可解的理念
but incomprehensible attraction.
四年中学
In four years of high school...
我们未交谈过半句
we haven't said one word to each other.
机上你预感到危险 我也预感到
At that moment,on the plane,I felt what you felt.
你发慌 我才察觉是什么危险
I didn't even know where those emotions came from...
你能够预见危险 我不能够
until you started freaking out.
我只能预感危险
I didn't see what you saw,but I felt it.
危险仍未消除 对不对?
You can still feel it,can't you?
那日所发生的事仍未完结
Something from that day is still with you.
你预感到 我也预感到
I know because I can still feel you.
所以我昨晚也去
That's why I was there last night.
我从未面对过死亡
I've never dealt with death before.
可能只是疑神疑鬼
This could all be in our head.
总觉得有异样
It just feels like it's all around us.
异样?
It?
我们或者难逃一死
What if Tod was just the first?
像托德一样
Of us.
这是你的预感?
Is that something that you're feeling?
不知道
I don't know.
假如可以再见到托德见他最后一面…
I wish I could see him one last time.
或者可以弄明白
Maybe I would know.
想见他 就去见好了
Then let's go see him.
小心
Easy.
我的心跳得很快
Gives me a rush.
因为这个地方?
This place?
因为做不应该做的事
Doing something I'm not supposed to.
跟我来
Come on.
快点
Hurry up.
- 是他? - 我想是的
- Is that him? - I think.
为什么化妆成麦克尔?杰克逊一样?
Why did they make him up like Michael Jackson?
就是他
That's him.
他已经不是托德了
Whatever it was that made him Tod is definitely gone.
天啊!
Holy Christ!
不要吵
Please.
吵醒长眠的人
You'll wake the dead.
他的手为什么动?
Why'd his hand do that?
化学剂…
Chemicals.
在血管流动 令到尸身抽搐
The vascular flush creates cadaveric spasms.
是这样的 我是他的朋友…
Look,I'm his friend...
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
为什么有这瘀痕?
What are all those tiny marks?
被铁丝勒到皮下出血
Cuticle lacerations from pulling at the wire.
铁丝?
Pulling at the wire?
他不是死于自杀
If he was pulling at the wire,he didn't kill himself.
是死于意外
It was an accident.
人 没有横死这回事
In death,there are no accidents...
也没有枉死 惨死
no coincidences,no mishaps...
只有注定的一死
and no escapes.
我们就像一只老鼠
What you have to realize is we're all just a mouse...
被猫玩弄于指掌之间
a cat has by the tail.
我们无论做什么
Every single move we make...
鸡毛蒜皮 抑或丰功伟绩
from the mundane to the monumental...
停红灯 抑或冲红灯
the red light that we stop at or run...
跟谁做情人 抑或做陌路人
the people we have sex with or won't with us...
搭飞机 抑或下飞机
aeroplanes that we ride or walk out of...
都属于死亡程序 由死神…
it's all part of death's sadistic design...
预先设计的程序
Ieading to the grave.
预先设计?
Design.
也就是说 如果洞悉了设计…
Does that mean if...
就可以逃出鬼门关?
you figure out the design,you can cheat death?
艾力克斯 你一下飞机
Alex,you've already done that...
就已经逃出来
by walking off the plane.
现在你朋友已经死去…
Your friend's departure...
这就是说 死神为你们准备另一套新设计
shows that death has a new design for all of you.
你想活命 就要猜测…
Now you have to figure out...
自己会怎样死 几时死
how and when it's coming back at you.
艾力克斯 劫数难逃
Play your hunch...
你想逃 唯有凭直觉
if you think you can get away with it.
不过 记住…
But remember...
欺诈和不尊重此设计
the risk of cheating the plan...
可引致愤怒
of disrespecting the design...
和恐吓你的内心
could incite a fury to terrorize even the Grim Reaper.
你根本不想知道个中道理
And you don't even want to fuck with that Mack Daddy.
好了 到此为止
OK,then.Well...
我们偷进来 对不起
I'm sorry we broke in,and...
不知者不罪
No harm,no foul.
很快会再见你
I'll see you soon.
那个殡仪佬说 死亡是经过设计的
The mortician said that death has a design.
即是有迹可寻
I'm talking about omens.
我们坐在这里
How do we know,that just by sitting here...
喝咖啡 呼吸…
by sipping this coffee or breathing the air...
有可能引起
or even crossing the intersection...
一连串事件…
we haven't started in motion...
最终导致我们若干年后死亡?
the events that will some day lead to our death...
40年 10年 明天 几时死…
forty years from now,ten years,tomorrow?
我们不知道 除非我们留意蛛丝马迹…
We don't,unless we open ourselves up...
及早洞悉那设计
to the signs it's willing to show us.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你有没有预见托德死去?
Did you see Tod die?
就像在机上预见爆炸一样
Did it happen again,like on the plane?
没有预见 但有预兆
No,it didn't,but it might as well have.
从预兆也可以…
This is a message from something,Clear...
揣摩出设计端倪
or someone,hinting at a design.
胡说八道
Total bullshit.
要找预兆 到处都找到预兆
You can find death omens anywhere you want to.
咖啡是黑色 黑色代表死亡
Coffee starts with a "C" and ends with an "E".
那又怎样?我们喝咖啡而呛死?
So does "choke." We'll choke to death?
你的看法有一定道理
I want to hear you...
但不可以捕风捉影 走火入魔
but we'll go nuts if you start with this shit.
殡仪佬说 死是预先设计的
The mortician said that death has a design,right?
我可能无意中预见了那设计…
Now,what if you,me,Tod,Carter...
令你 我 托德 卡特…
Terry,Billy,Mrs Lewton messed up that design?
泰莉 比利 刘老师…
For whatever reason,I saw death's plan...
逃出鬼门关
and we cheated it.
即是说
But what if it was our time?
我们该死而没有死
What if we were not meant to get off that plane?
我们仍然大限临头
What if it still is our time?
果真如此 我们迟早死于非命
If it is,then it's not finished...
而且早死多过迟死
and we will die.Now,not later.
除非及早察觉蛛丝马迹 再逃出鬼门关
Unless we find the patterns and cheat it again.
听完你这样说…
After hearing you,I do believe...
我相信托德自杀
that Tod killed himself.
卡特 不要烦他
Baby,come on,not now.
人全到齐了
Looks like we have a reunion here.
算了吧
Let it go.
- 几时搬走? - 几个星期后
- When are you moving? - Couple weeks.
- 可惜… - 该死的
- That's too bad. - Carter,you dick!
我们失去一位良师
Losing our favourite teacher.
我们走吧 我有话说
Guys,there's something I need to tell you.
你要离乡别井 你们不可不信
Lived here your whole life,and now she's gotta move...
我们都有危险!
We're in danger!
不要吵闹了!你们两个
Enough! Both of you!
人死不能复生
They died,and we lived.
我们还活着
Get over it.
坠机的事
I will not let this plane crash...
我不会耿耿于怀
be the most important thing in my life!
天啊!
God!
我要过新日子 卡特
I'm moving on,Carter...
你一定要浪费时间…
and if you want to waste your life...
专找艾力克斯霉气 那么…
beating the shit out of Alex every time you see him...
你不如干脆死掉好了
then you can just drop fucking dead!
艾力克斯在吗?
Is Alex there?
克莱尔 他在 等一等
Hi,Clear.Yeah,just a minute.
克莱尔又打来 接听吗?
It's Clear again.You want to talk to her?
克莱尔 他在洗澡
Clear,he's in the shower.
我叫他再打给你
Can I get him to call you back?
好的 再见
Sure.Bye.
她担心你
She's concerned about you.
我也担心你
I'm concerned about you.
为什么不跟她谈?
Why won't you talk to her?
不跟我谈?
Or to me?
爸爸 你和妈妈很关心我
Dad,you and Mom have both been a big help...
但我暂时没话说 有些问题…
but there's something I need to understand...
我自己要先
before I can talk.
想通想透
To anyone.
运输安全局…
The National Transportation Safety Board...
就180号班机的爆炸成因…
has a new theory tonight on the cause of the explosion...
提出另一解释
of Volee Air flight 180.
某个发动机的电路绝缘体…
Officials believe deterioration of silicone insulation...
可能出现剥落 导致…
on an electrical connector to the scavenger pump...
易燃液体泄漏…
may have leaked combustible fluids.
托德的座位
That's Tod's seat.
接触到电制的火花
A spark beneath the coach cabin in the fuselage...
燃烧起来
may have ignited the fuel line,proceeding to the fuel pump...
从而引起爆炸
which would have set off the catastrophic explosion.
爆炸的途径
The path of the explosion.
首先是托德 然后是泰莉
First was Tod,then it was Terry.
死亡秩序照旧
They're dying in the order they would've died.
死亡设计
That's death's design.
下个轮到柳敦老师
Ms Lewton's next.
我一睡着就梦见泰莉
Whenever I can fall asleep,I see Terry Chaney...
光天化日 突然…
and in the day,out of nowhere...
脑里响起自己的声音
I hear the sound of my own voice in my head...
我对拉利说…
saying to Larry Murnau...
你懂法语
"No.You know the whole French thing.
你上机吧
"Get on the plane."
当日的情形 我总是念念不忘
Everything reminds me of that day.
是的
Right.
嗯 所以打算搬走 换换环境
Yeah. I'm hoping a change will help.
只是…
It's just that...
但我生于斯 长于斯
I lived here my whole life,you know?
一草一木都是愉快的回忆
And everywhere I looked were great memories.
现在 我只见到拉利和那班学生
And now all I see is Larry and those kids.
望出去前院
Just looking out my own front yard...
我已经不寒而栗
makes me feel nothing but fear.
罗拉 我再打给你
Laura,I'm going to have to call you back.
好的
Right.
我是瓦莱丽·柳敦 请问希瑞克探员在吗?
This is Valerie Lewton.I need Agent Schreck.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我只是…
I was just...
查查车胎 看看安不安全
checking the air in the tyre to make sure it's safe.
上车
Get in the car.
绑好安全带
Put on your seat belt.
我相信…
I believe that...
下一个是柳敦老师
that Ms Lewton is next.
下一个?
Next?
对 下一个
Yeah,next,because...
因为有个模式
there's this pattern that's occurring.
模式?
Right.A pattern.
你也察觉到?
You noticed that,too?
妈妈爱听的
Mom's favourite.
什么模式?
So what about this pattern?
你又预见到什么?
Did you see it in one of your visions?
突然心血来潮?
Did you catch it in some TV static?
我没有故弄玄虚
I never asked for what happened on the plane.
你们要嘲笑
You guys are going to sit there and make fun of me.
尽管嘲笑好了
Whatever.It's fine.
但我的确救了机上六条人命
But I saved six lives on that plane.
同学个个
Six lives,and everybody in my entire school...
当我怪物
thinks I'm a freak.
我并没有受惊过度
I'm not suffering from post-traumatic stress.
也不以为自己是耶稣再世
I don't have a narcissistic deity complex.
我不是杀人狂魔
I'm not going Dahmer on you guys.
只是照实直说
This just is.
我们人人都有个模式
There is a pattern for us all.
你有 你也有
There is a pattern for you.
人人都有设定模式
There is a design for everyone,and I don't know how yet...
我决定破解这个谜
but I'm going to break this one.
飞机爆炸
You came to our attention...
你难避嫌疑
because you were under suspicion in this plane explosion.
不过…
Now...
我知道你没有下手
I know you didn't blow up the plane.
于是追寻其它线索
We were ready to move on...
但生还者一个个死去
but then the other survivors started to die.
首先是你朋友托德
First,your friend Tod...
跟着是泰莉 当时你在场
then Terry Chaney,while you were at the scene.
今晚 你在柳敦小姐家外出现
And tonight,we pick you up at Val Lewton's house.
谁也不能够控制生死
Nobody has control over life and death...
除非是杀生或者寻死
unless they are taking lives and causing death.
你可以保证再不搞出人命?
Can you promise me no one else is going to die?
不 我不能
No,I can't.
被扣留着 怎样保证?
As long as I'm in here,it's out of my control.
对不起
I'm sorry.
好吧 你走吧
Go ahead.Get out of here.
谢谢
Thank you.
这小子还真邪门
That kid gives me the creeps.
我们没证据控告他
What do we do? We got nothing.
我不是指控告
That's not what I'm talking about.
刚才有好几次…
There were a couple of moments...
我差点相信他
where I almost believed him.
老实说 有时…
Don't take this the wrong way...
我觉得你也邪门
but sometimes you give me the creeps.
神经衰弱 这只是一只杯子
You've got to stop this.It's a stupid mug.
你会离开这里
You're out of here.
很快你就离开这里
Pretty soon you'll be gone.
离开这
You'll be gone.
柳敦老师
Ms Lewton.
什么事?不要动
All right,just stay still,OK?
柳敦老师
Oh,God,Ms Lewton.
真有你的
Dude.
我不知道他的下落
I don't know where he is.
他不理我
He's not talking to me.
为什么?
Why?
因为我不相信他
Because I didn't believe him.
假如有他消息…
If he does contact you,I think it would be...
为了自己安全 你要通知我们
in the best interest of your safety if you called us.
打上面那个电话
Now,here's my card.
是免费的
Toll-free number.
很有创意
lnteresting work.
卡特 该死的!
Carter,you dick!
做什么?
What are you doing?
刻上泰莉的名字
Terry should be on this wall.
妈的!
Shit.
为什么要来这里见面?
Why'd you want us to meet you here?
因为警探在监视我 等我找艾力克斯
They're watching me to see if I go to Alex.
所以你要带我去见艾力克斯
That's why you're taking me.
为什么?
Why would I want to see him?
因为他知道下个轮到谁
Because he knows which one of us is next.
不要超速 知不知道?
Drive the speed limit,OK?
不要从右边调头
And don't pass on the right.
比利 我有预感
Billy,wait a minute.I'm getting a vision.
下个轮到你
You're the next one,man.
为什么?
Man,why'd you say that?
因为你再出声 我宰了你
Because if you say another word,I'll fucking kill you.
(意外调查现场)
(琼斯海滩 州立公园)
这里起一英里内 可能找到他
He could be anywhere from here to a mile down the road...
你从那边找 我们在中间会合
so you guys start that way and meet back in the middle.
分头找寻 省一半时间
It'll take half the time.
他们会不会还在天上?
Do you think they're still up there?
灵魂会不会还在180班机里?
Somehow,flight 180,are they still in flight?
会不会活在另一个世界?
Somewhere...are they safe?
我小时候…
When I was a kid,like six or seven...
六七岁 很担心失去父母
I used to worry so much about my parents dying.
晚上醒来 睡不着
Lying awake at night,just worrying.
好多小孩都有这样的心理
Most kids do,I guess.
好多小孩都未失去父母
Most kids never have it happen.
我十岁
When I was ten...
爸爸去商店买烟
my dad went into a 7-11 for cigarettes.
听到有人说:不要转身
He heard someone say,"Don't turn around."
他以为是朋友开玩笑 转了身
On reflex,or thinking it was a friend joking,he did.
立即被人轰掉脑袋
A guy blew his head off.
从此 我们苦不堪言
Life became shit after that.
妈妈挨不住巨变 再嫁
My mom couldn't deal anymore.
继父是个混蛋
She married this asshole who my mom with my real dad...
以前 我父母绝不跟这种人来往
would have crossed the street to avoid this guy.
继父不要小孩
He didn't really want a kid...
妈妈只好撇开我
so my mom didn't,either,anymore.
假如死神给我家这样的设计…
If that was the design for my father and family...
那么 死神最好应该去死
then fuck death!
我经常希望有另一个世界
God,I have thought a lot about that somewhere.
在那世界
It exists,that place...
我爸爸平平安安
where my dad is safe.
那晚他已经有烟 不用去买
Where he had a full pack of cigarettes and kept driving.
我们一家三口 照常生活
Where me and my mom and my dad are still together...
完全不知道现在的情形
and have no idea about this life here.
而我们的同学还在天上
Where our friends are still in the sky.
人人都再有个生存机会
Where everyone gets a second chance.
艾力克斯 我们不可以放弃
Alex,we can't give up.
听着 我不可以回家
I can't go home,because after Mrs Lewton...
柳敦老师死了 警方在找我
they're looking for me.
我们载你到我爸的小屋暂避
We're taking you to my dad's cabin.
距些几里远
It's a couple of miles from my house.
你怎么这样神通广大…
Browning,you fucking warlock...
知道柳敦老师死去?
did you hear about Ms Lewton or what?
柳敦老师没死 我也不用躲藏
Why do you think I was hiding?
比利告诉警方 你从她家跑出来
Billy told the FBl he saw you running from her house.
我跑 因为警方怀疑我
I was running 'cause they blame me for everything.
怀疑我杀托德和柳敦老师
They blame me for Tod,for her...
炸飞机
for the fucking plane crash.
血液遇到火 凝固成血浆 艾力克斯
The fire caramelized her blood.
现场的血浆上有你鞋印 刀上有你指纹
Your shoe prints were in it,your fingerprints on the knives.
我已经解释过 我没有…
I told you they were not...
我什么都不管
I'm not talking about if you did it.
只想问你一句
Or even if you knew she was dead.
你是不是预先知道她是下一个?
Did you know she was going to be next before she was?
是 我预先知道
Yeah,I did.
预先知道
I knew.
好吧 我们这几个人之中…
All right,out of us...
谁是下一个?
who's next to see it?
拜托
Please...
我还未看足球决赛 不想死
tell me I'm going to see the Jets win a Super Bowl.
是我 对不对?所以你不回答
It's me,right? That's why you're not saying.
我连女孩都没摸过 不想死
I should have felt up Tammy in the pool that time.
罗嗦什么?他说下个轮到我
What are you whining about? I'm next!
他没说过 专心开车吧
He didn't say anything.Just drive.
我有权知道
You have a responsibility to tell me.
你知道 会好过吗?卡特?
Think it's easier to know?
不好过 只会他妈的更难过
It's not.It's fucking harder.
好不好过不关你事
You get off having control over me?
我自有主张
Let me decide how to deal with it.
谁先谁后 有什么分别?
It doesn't matter who's next...
我们个个都有份
'cause we're all on the same list.
混蛋
Fuck.
真的?
Really?
那就避也避不开 对不对?
Then why bother?
问题在哪?
What's the fucking point?
既然迟早去见泰莉
Me and Terry'll be back together on the other side...
还等什么?
so why wait any longer?
卡特 你做什么?
What are you doing?
卡特 慢点…
Carter,slow down.
- 慢点 卡特 - 去死吧!
- Slow down,Carter! - Fuck you!
停下!
Knock it off!
自杀好过被杀
May as well go out on my own free will!
我们不想陪死!
Not with us in the fucking car!
天哪 卡特!
Jesus,Carter!
卡特 停车!
Carter,stop the car!
未轮到你们 你们怕什么?
What's the fucking worry if it ain't your time?
下盏红灯我就停下
I can get nailed running this next red light.
死的只是我
You all wouldn't get shit.
未必只是你 卡特
It doesn't work that way!
早知不去巴黎!
I fucking hated French class!
- 不要发狂 - 我不是发狂
- Get control of yourself. - That's what I'm doing!
人人都会怕 又不是只有你才怕 卡特
I know what you're doing,and it's all right to be scared.
我不怕 我只是找死
I'm not afraid.I decide when it's time.
我是生是死 自己作主
I control my life.I control my death.
你死无所谓 但不用死充
You don't have to prove how big your balls are!
不要乱驶
Stop driving like such an asshole.
你做什么?
What are you doing?
你他妈的做什么?
Jesus Christ!
掌方向盘!
Put your hands back on the wheel!
- 卡特 不要乱来 - 卡特 掌方向盘!
- Carter,stop! - Back on the wheel!
混蛋
Shit.
卡特 冷静点
Carter,easy.
我差点吐出来了
I am so close to puking right now.
我们也怕 但不放弃
We're afraid,too,but we're not quitting.
不要乱来 快停车!
Stop it and stop this fucking car!
卡特 立即停车!
Damn it,I want you to stop this car right now!
- 开走 - 开门 比利
- Move it. - Open the door,Billy.
开走呀!
Move the fucking car!
- 他妈的 开门 - 快开走
- Open the fucking door. - Move the car.
- 妈的 快开门 比利 - 快把那该死门打开
- Can't you open the door? - Open the fucking door.
- 开门… - 比利 快开门!
- Open it! - Billy,open the door!
卡特 听我劝 不要自寻短见
Carter,listen to me.Don't do this.
下车吧 你这个混蛋
God damn it! Get out of the fucking car!
卡特 听我劝
Carter,listen to me!
不是这样的!
This isn't the way!
不要消极 下车!
It's not the way! Get out of the car!
火车来了!
It's coming!
未轮到我
It ain't my time.
混蛋
Shit.
听我劝 不要消极
Listen to me! This isn't the way.
下车!
Get out of the car!
快下车!
Come on! Get out!
我不能下车!
I can't get out!
真的轮到他了
Man,he really is next.
下车!
Get out!
见鬼!
Fuck!
哦 天哪!
Oh,God!
我预见到 预见到安全带!
I saw it! I saw the belt!
现在怕了没有?
You scared now?
他坏了
It broke!
预见到安全带断开!
Bullshit!
废话 他又救你一命
He saved your life again.
正解!
That's right!
下个轮到你 卡特!
You're next,Carter!
我有多远躲多远
I'm staying the fuck away from you!
- 给我闭嘴 - 还斗什么气?
- Shut up,Billy! - We don't need this shit now.
我再也不想这样了!
I don't need it ever!
不要被他拖下水!
Get away from him ! He's next!
混蛋 我还没死
Fuck you,Billy! I'm not dead!
你迟早玩完!
You will be.
你迟早要死
You're dead...
我不做陪死鬼!
and you ain't taking me with you!
- 上帝 不! - 该死的!
- God,no! - Oh,shit!
我的天哪!
Jesus fucking Christ!
本来轮到你
You should have been next.
柳敦老师之后本来轮到你
You were after Lewton.That's the plan!
你本来注定死!
That's the design! You should be fucking dead!
你是死神吗!
You're the devil!
我预见到安全带会断!
I saw the seat belt.I knew it would rip!
就像预见爆炸
That's how I saved him.
所以救到他!
Just like the explosion.I saw it!
- 警察快来了 - 见鬼 我救了他
- The police are coming. - Fuck! I saved him !
我救了卡特 死亡越过卡特
Because I saved him,it skipped Carter...
落在下个身上 落在比利身上!
and went to the next person in the path of the explosion!
故此 我如果预见死因…
I have to see it.
及早插手
Then I intervene...
就可以破坏死亡设计
and if I intervene,I cheat the design.
插手?你当自己是神?
Intervene? Are you God now?
神不怕死
God's not afraid to die.
神不会死! 我们才会!
Gods don't die! We do!
警察快来 你太激动了
Baby,you are losing it.The police will be here.
到我的小屋躲一躲
We have to get you back to my cabin.
冷静一下
You can hide out and get your head together.
好 比利之后轮到我
After Billy,I'm next.
下个是我
I'm next.
然后是我
Then me.
我怎也不会坐以待毙
Listen,I'm not going to let it happen.
听着
Listen to me.
你们两个还不走?
Why don't you two get the fuck out of here?
生锈
Rusted.
破伤风
Tetanus.
有创意
Nice one.
我一时失察
I overlooked it.
你想乘虚而入 但给我识穿
You tried to capitalize,but I caught you.
去你的!
You fuck!
我有办法斗赢你
I can beat you.
但不能够长斗长胜
Maybe not forever...
我在这间屋内 陪你好好玩玩
but I got this cabin rigged to beat you now!
(1986年 我和爸爸摄于小屋)
刚才还见到她
She was there a minute ago.
什么?
What are you talking about?
我不是帮你们拘捕他
I'm not turning him in.
只是希望你们保护他
It's too dangerous for him out there alone.
我带你们去
I go with you.
不可以
You can't.
你只要说出他匿藏地点
Just tell us where he is.
你先回家等
Wait at home.I give you my word...
我们会把他带回来 加以保护
we will bring him in safely in protective custody.
(教师神秘烧死 余生者涉嫌)
(家长设立纪念助学金)
我没有换过位
I never moved.
姬丝黛叫我换位
Christa asked me to change,but I never moved.
但我没坐在托德旁边
I would have been up next to Tod.
混蛋 为什么现在才察觉?
Fuck! Why didn't I remember that?
我没换过位 克莱尔坐在我前面
I never moved.Clear's seat was in front of mine.
下一个轮到她
She's next.
上车!沿湖畔开!
Get in the car! We're going around!
- 在那里! - 追!
- There! - Come on,let's go!
艾力克斯 我们想帮你!
Alex,we're trying to help you.
走开!
Prince! Get away from it!
不要动!
Hold on!
跑!
Run!
给他逃脱了
We lost him.
他向那处走 必定去克莱尔家
From the direction,there's only one place he's heading.
糟了!
No shit.
哦 天哪!
Oh,my God!
不要动!
Don't move! Stay there!
不要动!什么都不要碰
Don't move!
别碰任何东西 车胎不导电
Don't touch anything.You're grounded by the tyres.
车快要爆炸
The car's going to explode!
我只能抓住电缆一会儿
I can only hold on for so long.You know what to do.
不要!
Don't!
你只要避过这一次就安全
When I do this,it'll skip you,and it'll all be over.
这是唯一逃出鬼门关的方法
It's the only way we can cheat death again.
不要!
Don't!
克莱尔 与其同归于尽
I am not going to let it beat us both.
不如我死你活
You know what to do!
我会长伴你左右
I'll always be with you.
不要!
Don't!
艾力克斯 走开!
Get away from there!
你不要死 不可以为我牺牲
Damn it! You can't do this to me.
活下去 艾力克斯
Come on,baby.Come on.
糟糕 他没有呼吸
Shit,he's not breathing.
不要死 艾力克斯 呼吸
Hold on,Alex.Come on.Stay with me.
(六个月后)
安全到达
Well,we made it.
巴黎 想不到啊
Paris.I can't believe it.
我们竟然再搭飞机
I can't believe we got on a plane again.
知道我想说什么吗?
Know what I'm saying?
想不到终于来到
It's weird being here,huh?
终于破解了天机
We finally completed a puzzle.
但我还未完全明白
It's just there's something missing.
知道吗?
You know?
泰莉
To Terry.
托德…
And to Tod.
所有来不到的朋友…
To all of our friends that can't be here.
向他们干杯
Cheers.
什么事?
What?
六个月前 我怎也不相信…
If you would've told me six months ago...
我们会在这里喝酒
the three of us would be sitting here having a drink...
我不知道 有时候 似乎…
I don't know.Sometimes it feels like...
只有你们才明白个中玄机
you two are the only ones who understand.
艾力克斯 你说得对
You were right,Browning.
死亡是早有安排的 我们躲避过去
It did skip us.There was a design.
我们跟死神斗 斗赢了
We beat it.We won.
我们更应该好好做人
The only thing we won is a chance at a full life.
不要浪费这机会
A chance that I won't ever waste.
有一点我还不明白
There's just something I can't figure out.
- 哪一点? - 关于死亡设计
- About what? - The design.
艾力克斯 算了吧 好不好?
Just let it go,all right?
姑且听我说说
Hear me out,all right?
- 又来了 - 爆炸的途径…
- Oh,my God. - Just listen.
决定我们死亡的次序
The explosion path determined the order of our deaths.
我插手 救了卡特
When I intervened and saved Carter...
死亡越他而过 降临在比利身上
it skipped him and went to the next person...Billy.
跟着是克莱尔
Then it was Clear.
但我插手 救了她 于是轮到我
But I intervened and saved her,so it went to me.
但没有人插手救我
But in my case,no one intervened,right?
我拿着电缆
I was thrown from that power line...
被炸到弹开…
by the explosion,so...
你奇怪自己为什么死不去
So why did it skip you?
可能你注定命不该绝
How do we know this isn't what was meant to happen?
180班机里…
That out of everyone on flight 180...
你 我 卡特注定生存
you,me,and Carter were meant to live?
或者由始至终就是这样
Maybe that was the design all along.
- 否则 下个轮到你 - 闭嘴 卡特
- Or you could still be next. - Shut up,Carter.
规矩不是我订
I didn't make up the rules.
有人插手 死亡才越过去
Somebody's got to intervene before death can skip them.
艾力克斯三度插手 确有其事
Alex proved that three times with the plane,me,and you.
我们可能还要
For all I know,it could circle back...
轮着死
and get us all again.
不过我最安全
But I am the safest fucker in the world...
因为你还是下一个
because you're still next.
不要再提 好不好?
Can we just stop talking about this?
我们算一下…
Let's figure out...
回酒店吧
I'll meet you back at the hotel.
等一等 我跟你去
I'll go with you.
留下来 不要跟着来
No,just stay here,OK,Clear?
行不?
All right?
不出所料 你是下一个
See? It's true.I told you you were next,man.
闭嘴 卡特
Stop it,Carter.Alex,wait.
克莱尔 等一等
Clear,stay there,OK?
不要走过来
Stay away.
- 早说过 你是下一个 - 那就越我而去
- I told you you were next! - It skipped me.
下个轮到谁?
So who's next?